Hey, Joey. What'd your nonna
send you in here for today, huh?
Two loaves of bread and a dozen zeppole.
Zeppoles are hot and fresh.
They're coming right up, my friend.
Be good. Say the rosary.
Now, Joey,
don't eat 'em all before you get home.
Play ball!
I love your new car, Mr. Romano.
It's a classic.
Ah, thank you, Joe.
- Hey, Joey.
- Hey, Bruno.
Bruno. You missed a spot.
Get in there.
Mamma, I got the bread.
Bravo, Joey.
Zeppole.
Joey!
No zeppole.
Get outta here.
Joey, do you wanna come
see Nonna make the gravy?
Vieni cà.
Guarda, aspetta.
Smell.
- How do you know how much to use?
- You feel in your heart.
You put in your heart.
Mangia.
It's perfect, Nonna.
No. You areperfecto.
- "One does not grow old at the table."
- Mm-hm.
Hey! Get outta here!
- You like the lasagne?
- Who took all the corner pieces?
Hey, what happened to the lasagne?
- Do you call it sauce or gravy?
- Sauce.
Mm!
Mamma.
- Hey!
- Ah!
- Roberta! Oh my gosh!
- Ciao, Roberta!
Hey!
Roberta!
Fotografia!
No!
- Hey.
- Oh, I'm sorry for your loss, Joey.
Your mother had a heart of gold.
I made you stuffed shells
with fresh ricotta and spinach for later.
Thank you.
To your ma, Maria.
She was like my mother.
- Only nice.
- Yeah.
- Salute.
Hmm.
I don't know what, uh, tomorrow
is supposed to look like, Bruno, you know?
- Give it time.
- Yeah.
Gets better with time.
That wife of mine
just gave me the stink eye?
Yeah. Looks that way.
Here we go.
- Joe, I made you my scungilli.
- I told you he didn't like scungilli.
Would you shut up? You got a loud mouth.
You need to feed your grief.
It's the only way through.
Mm-hmm.
There's 18 cloves of garlic in there.
Thank you.
- I'll come by this week, okay?
- Okay.
I want you to take these and eat them.
Your famous cassatas.
Here, please.
Hmm.
- Delicious.
- Prego.
- You were one of my mom's favorites, Gia.
- Well, 26 years.
She was more than a client.
She was a friend.
I just wanna say thank you for everything.
You made her that beautiful wig.
Yeah, well, we all deserve our dignity,
especially at the end.
You know, if you need anything,
you know where to find me.
Yeah.
Okay.
- Refrigerate those.
- Yes.
Next Sunday, dinner.
- That wasn't a question.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Oh, wow.
- She looks beautiful, Bruno.
- Thanks to you.
Please. I love working on her.
Madone, the way you talk about this car,
I swear you'd marry this car if you could.
All right, all right. In, get in.
She's right. I'd marry the car.
I heard that!
Boy, a lot of good memories in there.
Remember my dad with the goddamn hubcaps?
Sucks losing 'em.
Yeah.
Call you tomorrow.
Yep.
Mi disgusta!
- Where's the oregano?
- Roberta, please.
- You call this Italian food?
- All right, all right.
- Joe!
- Come on, Roberta.
She's attacking me again.
- Roberta, come on.
- He calls this spaghetti and meatballs?
- It's deli meat and ketchup!
- Hey!
This is good stuff. See?
- Hey! Come on, stop.
- Get outta here!
Il diavolo! He's trying to kill me!
I want to kill you.
- Hope the family's good. Nice to see you.
- Good to see you, Joe.
- I know what you're gonna say.
- What? Stop abusing the chef?
- Abuse? Abuse the chef?
- Yeah.
The police are coming.
They got an assault charge against you.
Yeah, well, when my foot
gets better, he'll see abuse.
My foot right up hisculo.
Hey, I got something for you.
What?
She wanted to make sure
that I got this to you.
I couldn't, Joey. I…
I'm sorry, I…
I just couldn't bring myself
to go to her funeral.
I know.
Hey, it's okay.
It's okay.
For 60 years, she was my best friend.
And you were hers.
You know, you just can't say goodbye
to someone after 60 years.
It's just not possible.
She knew I loved this pin.
Come on, let's make... Put it on.
Be nice.
That's good.
I think it looks nice. Hmm?
Oh. Wait a minute.
I almost forgot.
It's a letter from your mom.
That's nice.
You'll know when you're ready.
And you'll open it then.
Thank you.
"One does not grow old at the table."
Hey, there he is!
The legend returns!
From the look of the outside,
it's probably just a battery line.
Should be a pretty quick fix this morning.
Are you trying to make the bus bad?
- It looks good.
- What is going on?
Better punch in quick.
Boss has been on the warpath.
Good to know nothing's changed.
- What's that? Smells good.
- Something I brought for the break room.
My nonna'spolpette,
or as close as I could possibly get to it.
Anyway, thanks for coming last week.
I appreciate you guys.
Hey, no matter how old you are,
there's nothing worse than losing your ma.
Hi, Mr. McClane. Good morning.
- Good to see you.
- Joe! Good to see you.
Got worried when you took
so many vacation days.
- Thought you'd never come back.
- No, that would never happen.
Good to be back. And, um…
Gosh, thank you so much
for remembering me with the fruit basket.
- You got it.
- Tangerines and stuff. Thank you for that.
Of course. I lost my cat last year,
so I understand the grieving process.
It's the least I could do.
Sorry about your cat. I didn't know.
Break's over.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Thank you again.
Joe, when I said Sunday dinner,
I didn't mean for you to cook for us.
Oh, stop it. I love having you guys here.
Okay. This is my nonna's.
It's a homemade pasta.
It's got pork cheek, Pecorino cheese,
and vine-ripened San Marzano tomatoes
for the pomodoro sauce.
- Well, I'm impressed.
- Since when are you so into cooking?
I don't know. Lately, I've been going
through all my ma and nonna's dishes,
the ones that I remember,
and just making them one by one.
I've gotten close on a few,
but it's my nonna's Sunday gravy.
I really wish I could figure
that one out. Anyway…
- Buon appetito.
- Well, it looks delicious.
Salute. Let's eat.
Look…
Just… Joe, before we eat,
there is something
Bruno and I wanna talk to you about.
She's very worried.
I hear about it 50 times a day.
Since your mother's gone,
I'm just worried about your future.
I mean, you took care of her for so long,
and it was beautiful,
but now it's time for you
to take care of you.
What does that even mean? I…
- Maybe you could chime in.
- All right, fine.
We're not kids anymore, right?
You need a plan.
- Take your mother's insurance.
- I don't even wanna talk about that.
I had to lose her to get the money...
It's not how I wanna spend my night…
I know... Joe, but the way
to honor her is to spend it.
Find something that makes you really happy
or something that makes you feel her.
Or take care of your debt.
$200,000 goes a long way.
- Okay.
- I don't know, maybe it's...
Maybe it's buying some new clothes
or, um, some furniture.
I mean, that chair.
Madone, that was Bruno's
before we were married.
- I like it. What's wrong with it?
- Great for watching Yankee games.
Shaped like a baseball glove.
100% Corinthian leather.
Okay, okay, maybe, I don't know.
Maybe a hobby. I have a friend
who just took up flamenco dancing.
Oh, stop it with the flamenco dancing.
He's not going flamenco dancing.
What about volleyball? You like it.
I guess. I don't know.
You mean, to play the volleyball?
I don't care what you do.
You gotta try something new.
If you keep doing the same thing,
the same is gonna keep happening.
I don't want you sitting in that
damn chair when you're 60.Capisce?
- Capisce.
- I'm sorry I'm nagging, just…
I worry because I love you.
- No, I know.
- Okay.
- I love you. Thank you.
- I love you too.
And I'm also very hungry, so let's eat.
- Nothing worse than a cold pork cheek.
- I'm excited for you to try this. Okay.
Hi, how are you?
Bellissimo.
Hmm.
- This is a nice one.
- Yeah.
My nonna used to do
the exact same thing with the…
Well, I mean,
the tomato's the heart of your dish.
- Don't have heart, don't have nothing.
- True story.
Okay, give me, uh, three of these.
- Three. Anything for you.
- Grazie.
- Prego.
- Okay, Antonella, I got the flowers.
- Oh, good. Oh, they're beautiful.
- Olivia?
Joe?
- Oh, my gosh. You look exactly the same.
- What?
Oh, come on. This is crazy.
- I mean it.
- Like, been 30 years.
No, I swear to God,
you haven't changed at all.
- You look terrific.
- Thank you.
You know this man?
Oh, sorry, yeah. Uh…
- Joe, this is my neighbor Antonella.
- Hi.
Joe and I went to school together
before my parents moved to Staten Island.
Yeah. I actually took, uh, Olivia to prom.
Yes, prom.
Hmm.
Oh.
Yep.
Ah.
It's, um, very nice
to meet you, Antonella.
Well, nice to meet you too. Thank you.
- You don't live on the island, right?
- Oh, no, no, no.
No, when I was a kid, my mom and nonna
would bring me to this market, so…
- I couldn't believe it was still here.
- Yeah, well.
- Great things stand the test of time.
- She's a lawyer.
- No, I'm not.
- A lawyer?
I mean, I'm not yet. I'm...
I went back to school.
I'm in my, uh, first year
JD program at St. John's.
- St. John's, that's impressive.
- Uh…
Yeah.
- Never too late to start all over again.
- Yeah.
- I don't wanna be rude. We're in a rush.
- Of course. Great to see you.
- Thank you.
- You too. Antonella, nice to meet you.
- Thank you. Nice to meet you.
- Thanks, Al.
What's going on?
That's a short but long story.
"Very short but long story."
- I love that phrase. Let's remember that.
- Okay.
Nice, Olivia from high school.
She still hot?
Hot and married.
- Who's still hot?
- I gotta go.
Okay. What are we doing here?
Giving the neighborhood a show?
What? I don't want any tan lines.
Hey, I got something
I wanna tell both of you guys.
I went to, uh, Staten Island
the other day, and I found a restaurant.
What are you doing
going to Staten Island to eat?
Yeah, there's lots
of good restaurants here.
Yeah, I'm not talking
about a restaurant to eat.
I'm talking about a restaurant to buy.
Huh?
- Restaurant to buy?
- Yeah.
- In Staten Island? What?
What the hell are you talking about?
How'd you buy a restaurant?
With the money my mom left me.
What? Are you crazy?
I don't know. Maybe I am.
But, look, I really do.
I wanna open an Italian restaurant,
and I wanna name it Enoteca Maria.
I wanna name it after my mom.
You don't know the first thing about it.
What is there to know? You make food,
people eat the food, people are happy.
- You told me I need to try something.
- Like buy new furniture, get a girlfriend.
Right, or pay your mortgage,
not start a business
you know nothing about.
Guys, I'm not getting any younger, okay?
And I'm running out of time
to figure this out, all right?
This is what I want.
I dunno how to explain it,
but this is what I need.
Listen, I cannot in good conscience
allow you to spend your ma's money
on a restaurant in Staten Island.
I don't think that you understand.
I already did.
Okay, listen, I'm really excited
for you guys to see this place.
It's pretty amazing, okay?
All right. Take a look.
This bar here, I mean,
look how cool that is.
Look at this floor.
This checkerboard, totally authentic.
It's not trying hard,
it just feels terrific.
I'm probably gonna take these booths
and clean them out. I don't need them.
- You spent how much on this?
- 175,000 for the down payment.
I mean, I have a mortgage, obviously.
I'm not gonna quit my job at the MTA.
I'll keep it in order to pay the bills.
And I have a solid five months of money
before I even sell one plate of food.
Oh, God!
Okay. Guys, honestly, can you just try?
Just try to keep an open mind.
Because if I don't have you two,
then I don't have anybody, okay?
Now, just walk the place with me
and share my vision. Can you do that?
Okay, this exposed brick right here,
people would literally kill each other
to have that nowadays.
There is a phone booth in the back room
that is just so cool and old-school.
Glance up at those tin-crusted ceilings.
Are you kidding me? That's real.
The way I see this is you would take down
all these walls, maybe put in an archway.
This would be
a beautiful open-air kitchen.
I want the entire place to feel more like
someone's house than a restaurant.
Okay, so, just so I can
wrap my brain around this,
you wanna open a restaurant
with the five dishes you kind of,
sort of know how to make?
No, maybe a dish or two from my family.
But you know what occurred to me?
This is what happened.
I'm going through
my mom's and my nonna's recipes,
and I'm like, "What is going on here?
Why am I searching so hard?"
And then I realized, right,
that food is love.
As long as I have their food,
I'm gonna have them.
I really do want the place to be about
more than just serving someone dinner.
I really, really want this place
to feel like family.
Okay, but Joe, your ma and your nonna,
they're not around.
So, who are you gonna get
to come down and cook like them?
Nonnas.
Other real-life Italian grandmothers.
That's who.
I want 'em to make dishes
that were passed on from their family.
And I wanna share it with everybody.
I love it!
What? I do.
Real-life grandmas!
- Joe, it's a wonderful idea.
- Oh.Thank you.
I mean, who wouldn't want
their grandmothers cooking?
All right, I can...
I can kinda see the appeal, I guess.
Come on, it's a great idea.
You love this idea.
No, I don't love it.
You love it, 'cause if you didn't love it,
you'd have nothing
but a cold, dead heart inside.
Yeah, Bruno.
Stop having a cold, dead heart.
A job like this would take months, okay?
The... The walls, the floor,
the tile, the electric.
Don't get me started on the plumbing
and the ANSUL system, okay?
Who you gonna get to do that work for?
Are you gonna hire a nonna for that?
No, I'm really fortunate, because
my best friend happens to be a contractor.
- So I'm fortunate.
- Oh, no. No, no.
- Yes, I am.
- No, no, no!
Not that I'm bringing this up because
I would never, ever bring this up,
but remember I fixed your father's car
out of the goodness of my heart?
- That's bringing it up.
- Only as a source of reference.
You're my best friend. I can fix cars,
and you needed a car fixed.
Cars don't need permits, Joe.
They don't need
building codes, union labor.
You're being impulsive.
You need chefs, a menu, a marketing plan.
You're gonna need
a certificate of occupancy.
You're gonna have to pass inspections.
- You're not even listening!
- I'm listening.
I gotta pass inspection
and I need to get menus.
I love you to death.
You are a lot of things,
but a responsible businessman
is not one of 'em.
I know that. That's why I got you.
I promise, I'm gonna pay you back
for all the work you do
the second this place is up and humming.
And I do love to decorate.
I see a wine rack over there
and like a little Benjamin Moore,
splash it up, and maybe
some family photos on the walls.
That's what I'm talking about.
She has a vision for this place already.
- That's exciting!
- You are a crazy son of a saint, you know?
Does that mean you'll do it?
- Yes, I'll do it.
- Come on, this is gonna be fun.
- All right, all right.
- You only live once.
- Don't touch me like that.
- Superman, look at the old phone booth.
Okay.
Joe, where's the bin? I need the bin.
God, I need a paying job. Let's go.
Ay, ay, ay.
What is this?
- A chef?
- Yeah.
Look at me, I can barely move.
What are you talking about?
The doctor says you're doing great.
What the hell does he know?
I gotta wear compression socks
to go from here to the bathroom.
I know how unhappy you are
when you're not cooking. It will be great.
- I'm 73 years old. I am done being happy.
- Come on. Age is not a disease, Roberta.
Yeah, well, it's not a cure either.
- Joey, I can't. I can't do this for you.
- I am not asking you to do this for me.
I'm asking you to do it
for you and for mymamma.
- What?
- God rest her soul.
You using Catholic guilt on me?
- I learned it from the best.
- Madone.
Look, I'm not saying yes,
but if I did say yes…
Mm-hmm.
…who else would be in the kitchen
cooking with me?
I couldn't feed a restaurant
all by myself.
Trust me, please.
This will be fun.
Hey.
All the locals are talking
about, uh, that new restaurant of yours.
Yeah, that's right.
I don't think we've been, uh,
formally introduced. My name is Joe.
I'm Al.
27 Hyatt Street. That was my best friend,
Dominic Spirito's place.
Every baptism, communion,
graduation, birthday, anniversaries…
They were all at Spirito's.
Dominic was there for over 50 years
before he passed away.
Ah.
I'm so sorry for your loss. I didn't know.
You threw his name in the street.
We were working on the building.
I didn't mean any disrespect whatsoever.
I don't trust people
who aren't from around here.
We're not Manhattan,
and we sure as hell ain't no Brooklyn.
You're on the island now, pal. You got it?
Yeah, I got it.
Gianni,
what should I tell you about today?
Well, I got up. I made breakfast,
and, um, I took a nap. That was nice.
And then I had lunch,
and now I'm here with you, my darling.
Hello?
Antonella, it's me.
Do we have a doctor's appointment today?
Because if we do, I'm not going
unless it's with the podiatrist.
No, we don't.
But you do have a job interview.
No.
I told you no.
All those old ladies
trying to be chefs, that's ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
It's a sin.
Oh. How is that a sin?
And you told me
that that Joe fellow was astronzo.
I didn't. I said he was an immature jerk
when we were 17. That's all.
All right, you're gonna have to give me
a really good reason why I should go.
Because you sit alone in this house,
and you got more life to live.
- I brought your favorite wrap.
- I'm not going.
I took a water pill about an hour ago.
Your bathroom better be working.
You think I don't have a bathroom?
Oh, look at you with the walking.
Should be a light day.
I mean, everything's ready to go.
Thanks, guys.
Listen, nobody coming.
Everyone will be here in 20 minutes.
Sit and relax. You're doing so good.
- This list of Craig.
- No, it's Craigslist.
This Craig, is he reliable?
No, no, it's not a he, okay? It's an it.
It's a place where people kinda, you know,
post things they're selling
or like job descriptions.
Like the newspaper.
Yes, except it's online, right?
It's online, so anyone can go on
from anywhere and look at it.
- You should've put it in the papers.
- Uh… okay.
Roberta, do you know how my nonna
made her Sunday gravy?
There was always
this kind of sweet aftertaste.
Do you know the exact ingredients
that she would put into it?
Joey, that's like asking a woman
to show you hermundate.
Mundate? I don't even...
What kind of guy do you think I am?
- I don't even... What is amundate?
- Better not ask.
I'm sorry. I wouldn't ask
to see anyone'smundate,
but I've been kind of kicking myself,
I never had them
write any of this stuff down.
I don't know exactly,
and if I knew exactly,
it wouldn't have been
your nonna's gravy, would it?
It's the secret that makes it special.
Try sugar.
You need a lot more than you think.
- I put a ton of sugar in it.
- Well, there are different kinds.
You get the savory
when you find the sweet.
Okay, listen,
I made this entire scarf sitting here.
I hope you like it.
- For you.
- It's so nice. Thank you.
- You're welcome. Enjoy.
- Thank you.
- It's nice and warm for you.
- Super beautiful.
Okay, I'm calling the shuttle.
I got poker at 3:00.
No, no, no. Give me 20 minutes.
Listen to me. Will you stop?
- I gave you three hours.
- No.
I watched you move boxes.
See you move bottles.
Now, what's gonna happen,
is the other people are gonna join us…
- Nobody's coming!
- They're coming.
- Don't go. 45 minutes...
- I'm sick of watching you...
Look at this. You made it.
Isn't that great? Everyone made it.
This is great!
Calm yourself. She forced me.
Sometimes she needs
a little push out the door.
She literally pushed me.
- Here you go. Looks great. Your stuff.
- All right, I'm here.
- I got class. I'll come pick you up.
- What do you mean?
You have fun.
Huh?
Have fun.
Hey, thank you so much
for bringing her. I appreciate it.
Of course.
I'd do anything in the world for her.
By the way,
it's a really great idea. I hope it works.
Thanks.
All right.
Well, Antonella, this is Roberta
and she is a chef at Enoteca Maria.
Se.
Se?
So you're Sicilian?
Se.I'm from Sicily.
- And where are you from?
- I am from Bologna.
- Bologna.
- Sì.
Hmm.
I spit on Bologna!
- Is that so?
- Se!
Well, I spit on Sicily, okay?
Don't you spit on Sicily!
This is great!
This is like music to my ears.
Ah, no, no, no! Passion's good.
- You got thegrande bocca!
- You are a put tan a.
- Oh, hi. How are you?
- What? What do you want?
I think I have the wrong address.
No, no, you're at the exact right place.
I'm so sorry. Are you here to be a chef?
- Yes.
- Don't say that! Not nice!
Excellent. What is your name?
- Didn't say that.
- Teresa.
Teresa. What a beautiful name.
May I invite you to join the other ladies?
- I never met anybody like you.
- Get lost, you old bag!
Teresa, will you come join Antonella.
She's from Bologna, she is from Sicily.
- This is Roberta.
- Hello.
- And where are you from?
- Uh…
- Well, actually, I'm from the Bronx.
- Great.
Just have fun and cook like you're cooking
for your own family, all right?
The kitchen is yours.
What?
- You need some garlic?
- No!
Lazy Mary, you better get up
She answered back I am not able…
Stop. Stop.
No, no.
There.
Lazy Mary you better get up
We need the sheets for the table
Lazy Mary you smoke in bed
There's only one man you should marry
My advice to you would be
Is to pay attention to me
Hmm!
Oh, my God.
This cheese is perfectly crisp and yet
stays so gooey on your pizza, incredible.
Grazie.
Roberta, I mean, that oxtail stew
just melts right in your mouth.
Yeah.
So beautiful.
I'm not talking to you.
I'm not even talking to you.
Where did you come from?
Did you fall out of the sky somewhere?
You have that beautifully seasoned garlic,
but it's right inside the steak.
Where did you learn to do that?
At the convent.
Convent? Are you a nun?
- And you with that language.
- A blessed calling.
- Yes, sure.
- Well, I'm a retired nun.
I served for many years
at the CFR convent in the Bronx.
- Oh.
If it's okay to ask, why'd you leave?
Well, I loved my devotion. I just thought
it was time for something new.
And a friend's son
saw your ad in the list.
Craig, the bum.
Stop.
And I felt God was speaking to me,
telling me to come.
Giving me a… another chance.
So, Joe, who's got the job?
All of you guys.
- This is incredible.
- Oh!
We got a Murderers' Row here.
Look at this.
Are you kidding me?
I wish we could open the doors today.
Cheers, salute.
I'm so grateful.
Look, I've given you a ton of leeway,
and you keep showing up late.
Okay? So I can't do it anymore.
This is your last warning.
Okay.
Uh oh!
Oh, there he is. Dead man walking.
Got called at the principal's office.
I gotta ask you guys a favor.
- Yeah, sure.
- Whatever you need.
I just got written up again,
and I cannot lose this job.
So, do you mind covering for me with Dan?
Because I'm gonna be late to work a lot.
Why, Joey? What's going on?
Can you keep a secret?
Fourteen…
Let's see.
- Ah, no.
- Well, I had to.
Refinance your ma's home. What's next?
Next is Enoteca Maria has to work
because there's no other option.
You got me in a difficult position.
I'm one of the people you owe money to.
I know, but you're also my friend.
I need someone to talk to. Complicated.
I need you to think this through.
If you get out now, you could break even.
But if you stay in and it fails,
you could lose everything.
Bruno, I have this feeling deep in my gut
that this whole thing is gonna pay off.
You're my best friend,
so you stay, I stay.
I appreciate it. We got great chefs.
We got food from all over Italy.
- Gotta make sure you get good desserts.
- Yeah. We just passed that place.
I'm getting stressed with the talking.
I'm gonna crush a sub.
- I could do a cutlet.
- You wanna do a cutlet? Come do a cutlet.
Here's what I'm thinking. We can always
get desserts that are homemade.
What?
Just hear me out on this, okay?
You're a terrific baker.
The stuff you make is incredible.
It brought my mom so much joy.
I'm just asking you to share that.
I bake for fun. I don't bake serious.
This should be fun. Do something that's
fun for you and fun with everybody else.
- I like doing hair. That's my job.
- You have a job, and you're good at it.
But you have other gifts. This is a chance
to do something that you love.
Sweetie, it sounds exciting,
but I… I really can't. I'm sorry.
I can't even hear that.
I know this is the right thing.
- Is begging gonna help?
- Oh. Damn it.
- Are you okay?
- Damn it, damn it. My hands are going.
Some days are worse. I don't know
how much longer I'll be able to do this.
I'm so sorry. I didn't know
your hands were bothering you.
Is that something ongoing?
Sorry you're in that.
Don't be sad for me. Do not be sad for me.
I've led a great life
exactly how I wanted to,
and you know the stories,
and I have no regrets.
And, uh…
I am okay.
Yeah, well, you deserve
to be better than okay.
You deserve to be great.
We only have so much time,
so let me just accept this yes.
I'll see you tomorrow at the restaurant.
Don't let me down. Love you and thank you.
You are so manipulative.
Don't hold your breath.
Appreciate your patience. Love the color.
Gia, who wants to start over at this age?
This is my main dish on the menu.
What is that? It stinks.
Capuzzelle.
Dear God, save us.
- That is definitely a bold choice.
- How are you gonna put that on a menu?
Are you crazy?
Capuzzelleis from my family village.
Capuzzelleis my identity.
Well, change your identity.
Hey, wow, I'm so glad you made it.
I'm here.
This is Gia. She's our pastry chef.
- And you know Roberta, obviously.
- Oh yeah.
- This is Teresa and, uh, Antonella.
- Hello.
Ladies.
- Apron?
- Please. They're right over here.
Thank you.
Pa-pa-pa-pa. They bounce.
Hey, I… it's an apron,
not an evening gown.
Well, every opportunity
is an opportunity to look good.
How do you bake over those things?
Years of practice.
Wow.
- Okay, where were we?
- Mi capuzzelle.
Oh, that's what smells.
I thought maybe it was me.
Oh, God.
Wasn't sure.
- No.
- What iscapuzzelle?
Okay, so it's a simple story.
My mother came from a village
that was very, very poor.
So they had to use the entire animal.
So, you stuff the head
with some crumbs of bread.
Breadcrumbs.
Mi scusi.
- Breadcrumbs.
- Hmm.
A little of this, a little of that.
In the oven, thecapuzzelle.
Bye-bye, baby.
All right, the sheep's head is in.
Now, let's move on to sauce.
Oh, oh, oh, my mother's sauce.
Yes, of course, your mother's sauce,
or your nonna's sauce,
or your Great Aunt Mary's sauce,
as long as it is your family's sauce.
Thanks.
- We'll do cannolis for dessert.
- Great.
Perfect.
Gia, can you do me a favor?
Do you mind tasting all of these?
Tell me which one you think
should be on the menu? You be the judge.
Oh, sure. Well, if they taste
half as good as they smell,
this is gonna be difficult.
- Yeah, but just be honest.
- Okay.
- Is this your nonna's?
- No.
I mean, I tried maple syrup, brown sugar.
I tried honey.
There's just no combination I do
that makes it taste like my nonna's gravy.
- Well, you keep trying.
- Yeah.
Hmm. Is that almonds in there?
Sì, pesto alla trapanese.
From Sicily.
Bah!
They're all so good. I don't know
how you're gonna choose. They're perfect.
Joe, we could rotate the sauces
week to week.
- That's a great idea.
- Fabulous.
That's exactly what we'll do.
Let's taste what you were doing.
- Pesto alla trapanese, huh?
- Sì.
My people created Parmigiano Reggiano.
That's something to boast about!
- Parmigiano Reggiano.
- That's right.
My people created the cannoli!
- Cannoli? Are you crazy? It's nothing.
- Yes!
- What do you mean nothing?
- Stuffed cream for Christ's sake.
- What do you know?
- Get outta here.
You think you know everything
'cause you're from Bologna!
- Listen to this.
- Your people are mean and ugly and cold.
Your people are crude and vulgar.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Puttana.
And don't you spit any more at me
'cause you're gonna pay a debt for that.
Let me tell you right now,
you make something outta this.
You… What?
- Uh-huh. Yeah.
- You wanna fight?
Yeah.
How's this?
I'm going to throw something at you,
you beast.
What? How dare you?
- Oh, see if…
- How dare you?
I'm worried. I'm scared of you.
All right, go ahead. Go get it!
They could hurt themselves, Joe.
You've gotta stop this.
- No, let them fight it out.
- It's the Italian way.
Have a little arugula!
- Madre di Dio.
- Why don't you? Go ahead.
- Puttana! How dare you?
- Ow! Oh!
Ow!
I'm going to get you.
Mi capuzzelle!
This is a violation
for fire code defiance.
Your ANSUL system was shut off.
You're lucky no one got hurt.
Yeah. Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh my God. Look at that.
I'm already supposed to be somewhere.
So if we're all wrapped up,
if you don't mind, I'd love to get going.
Oh! Of course. You know,
I don't wanna hold up your day.
Okay, thank you so much.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry too, Joey.
It was her fault.
It's her fault.
You are killing me.
I still believe in you.
Maybe one good idea we can take from this
is not to fight in the kitchen, okay?
So sorry. I'm late for work.
I gotta run. Bye. Love you guys.
Can't you two just offer
to forgive each other?
To forgive is divine.
Oh, she started it.
Hey, Vito, Joe punched in.
Have you seen Joe?
How you doing, Mr. McClane?
He was here like, two hours ago?
Yeah, two hours ago.
I think he's over in maintenance
with Luis in North Garage.
Okay, thanks.
Hey, Luis, where's Joe?
Right, thank you.
I called you a putz.
Omar, where's Joe?
I'm not sure.
He was helping me mount some tires.
My guess is he's back
at the main depot with Vito now.
- You're kidding me!
- Yeah.
Vito, where the hell is Joe?
Mr. McClane, where you been all day?
That's lunch!
- Wow.
- Hey.
I love what you've done with the place.
- Yeah. You like it?
- You're crushing it.
I was thinking,
should I do that room and set that on fire
and just connect the two places?
- Too much.
- Yeah?
Antonella sent me.
She wants you to have
this card from the dollar store.
And I think there might be $20 in that.
- Very nice. Look at that.
- Yeah.
Roberta gave me $10, so I'm actually
gonna come out ahead in this one.
Yeah, wow. Lucky you.
A little Italian lightning
struck the place.
I wanna help clean.
Where's your trash bags?
Oh, um, just underneath there.
Okay.
Thanks.
No, really? That's crazy.
So, what was she taking?
Butter.
No, I'm serious.
The plastic square butters from the diner.
Trust me,
I know exactly what you're talking about.
My mom used to do the exact same thing.
Yeah, well, Antonella's fridge?
Filled with them.
I asked her, like,
how much butter does one person need?
How long have you and, uh,
Antonella been neighbors?
Oh, God, what?
My husband and I bought
the house next door… eight years ago?
And then it was a fixer-upper,
so we renovated.
And she complained
about the noise every day.
Well, you must've gotten past it,
'cause you two seem very close.
Yeah.
Yeah, she, um…
After my husband passed away,
she was amazing.
She wouldn't leave me alone.
She would come over and sit with me,
and cook for me,
and make me take a shower.
It's a special kind of love, you know?
Olivia, I am so sorry to hear that.
I had no idea.
Oh, come on, stop. How would you know?
She keeps telling me I should move
my wedding ring to the other hand, but…
I don't know. I just don't feel ready.
You know?
Yeah. Trust me, I understand.
Yeah?
My mom left me
this letter, but I haven't opened it yet,
because I feel like once I do open it,
that'll be the last thing
she ever says to me, you know, so…
Joe…
I'm sorry.
It just hurts.
Grief.
It doesn't have a timeline,
so why should we?
Yeah.
Hey.
Sturdy, isn't she?
Completely gutted.
Built from the ground up.
Every piece of wood, every piling.
- Yeah.
- Top-notch.
Okay, um… You're the owner?
Yeah. Yes.
You failed. Twice.
What?
Yeah, um, first of all,
there was a kitchen fire that's affecting
the integrity and safety of that wall.
No. That's impossible. There's no fire.
There was a… little bit of a problem
with a sheep's head, but…
A what?
And number two, you need a new oven
because you got remnants
of carbon dioxide and nitrogen in there.
That's easy. I can run out
and grab the new oven right now.
- We can take care of that off the list.
- It's a custom-made specialty oven.
You can't just pull up to a store
and have them throw it in your trunk.
On the bright side, your sprinkler system
is working fine, so, you know…
Have a good day.
I'm so sorry.
Would it be possible to do anything else
we could do to keep this moving?
- I really need to get these doors open.
- You can reapply for inspection.
Great. And what are we talking about?
What works for your schedule?
Would that be later
this week or next week?
Oh, sorry.
I like this guy. "Next week."
Um… Try "next year."
The waiting list is a mile long, pal.
You're not opening any time soon, man.
If ever.
There was a sheep's head fire?
What the hell does that even mean?
- Roberta with hercapuzzelle.
- Why didn't you tell me?
I… Honestly, I didn't think it was…
I didn't think it'd matter.
It was just a fire. I cleaned it up...
Joe, a sheep's head catches fire
compromising the integrity
of the walls I built?
- Right.
- Don't think it's important to tell me?
Okay. Bruno. Let's just calm down.
- Everyone's upset. I'm upset.
- I am calm.
- Okay. Good.
- Okay?
- But listen to me.
- I'm listening.
If you fail an inspection, that's it.
You have no certificate of occupancy.
You can't run a restaurant
if you don't have a building.
I'll find another way.
I'll find another way to keep it going.
With what money?
You don't have any money left!
I could take out a loan
against my pension.
Joe, listen to yourself.
I got credit cards.
I can take out credit cards.
No! You rushed into this thing,
didn't think it through,
and now we're both in the hole.
You're never gonna learn!
- What are you talking about?
- You've been the same since we were kids!
- Leap before you look. Every time!
- What does that mean? This restaurant.
This is me trying.
I'm trying. Take a look.
Oh, no. This whole thing is a joke, Joe!
You really made your ma proud this time!
Yeah?
Go ahead and get out.
I didn't… I didn't mean it like that.
I'll pay your money back. All right?
I want you to get out.
Fine.
Forget it.
Forget you.
Thank you for coming over so last minute.
I really do appreciate your help.
Oh, don't thank me yet.
I'm not sure we're gonna find anything.
- Building codes are not my specialty.
- Yeah.
Something's better than nothing.
This is really the only chance I got,
so thank you.
Your place.
This is where you lived with your mom.
Well, yeah. I mean, well, my mom,
she was downstairs with my nonna.
So, I was kind of up here
kind of looking after her, but, um…
Yeah, you know.
It's nice. I'm starting to…
Maybe I'll get around
to giving it a paint job or something.
Thinking about some new furniture, maybe.
Don't get rid of this chair.
That's a great chair.
Ah!
Christmas. Your nonna made
this exact soup on Christmas.
That's right.
You and your family came over.
Not everybody was nice to us
when we first moved here,
but your mom and your nonna,
they always were.
Yeah. Well, you were easy to be nice to.
Which is why I feel even worse
about the way that I handled prom.
- That was a million years ago. We're 100.
- I know, but it was terrible.
I am such an idiot.
Do you know what I did?
Bruno and all the guys, we made a pact
that we were gonna go sneak out, right?
He had the booze, the parents' house,
and we lost track of time.
I tried to come back, and then…
Ah, the whole thing was just a mess.
And, uh… by the time I got back,
no Olivia.
Anyway, I don't wanna make it awkward,
after all these years, bringing it up,
but I did wanna say to you that I'm sorry.
I am.
Thank you.
I appreciate the apology.
- Well, salute.
- Salute.
So the long, complicated version is
we don't have a certificate of occupancy.
Well, can't you reapply?
Well, I already have, but…
- That could take weeks or even a year.
- Right.
- We could all be dead by then.
- I tried everything I could.
Olivia and I were looking
for different loopholes, but nothing.
I don't wanna go back to what I was doing.
What was that?
Nothing.
What is she doing?
Is she having a stroke?
Santo Padre Pio,
truly, I tell you.
Ask, and it will be given.
Seek, and you will be found.
Bless these women.
They have generations
of family in their heart.
And bless Joe, because he has a dream.
Bless us.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Ghost.
Now we wait.
Uh, Teresa?
What exactly are we waiting for?
A miracle.
Okay.
Hey, Joe.
I think you, uh, remember Phil.
Yeah, I know… Phil. Wow.
Phil?
Mr. Scaravella,
I'm so sorry for the misunderstanding.
Here is your, uh,
certificate of occupancy.
If you could just do us a favor
and, uh, get that wall fixed
and that, uh, oven replaced,
we'd really appreciate it.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Have a good day, everyone.
Oh!
I don't understand.
The place we didn't look
was Better Business Bureau.
Phil here, he's had 53 complaints.
You have to bribe him in order
to come back
and do a follow-up inspection.
- You can't prove any of that.
- I can, and I will.
How dare you?
- Get outta here!
- Fix the wall. Get a new oven.
Yes, consider it done.
- Beat it!
- God forgives you.
I told you so. A lawyer!
Oh, stop!
Brava!
Hey. Thank you.
- It's good news.
- Brava!
Be good. Say the rosary.
Okay. Say it for me, please.
- Hey.
- Hey. Here you go.
- It took you long enough.
- Sorry about that.
- Aren't you gonna come in?
- Sure.
Come on.
Close the door, please.
You're letting in a draft.
- Yeah.
- No... Joe.
Go sit down. You two have to talk.
Come on.
Look, your friend brought you zeppole.
Talk.
I'm staying out of it.
Clearly, there was mistakes
made on your part.
Um…
But from my side of the street, um…
I could've been more transparent
about the sheep's head
and the proceeding fire, so…
That's…
It's not like you…
Burnt down the restaurant
that I built for you or anything.
Maybe
destroyed my reputation as a contractor
throughout the entire five boroughs,
but I guess I can see how I may have
communicated in a harsh manner.
And that is something
that I am working on.
Well, we got our permit, so that's…
Well, good for you.
- I wish you a very successful life.
- It's exciting.
It's nice to be moving ahead
with loyal friends
who are ready to work and…
Tell him!
- I thought you were staying out of it.
- If you don't tell him, I will.
Tell me what? Who's telling me what?
He sold his father's car
to build your restaurant.
If this is you staying out, I wonder
what you being involved would look like.
You didn't do that.
Did you do that? Did you actually do that?
I'm staying out of it.
Bruno, did you sell your father's car
to build my restaurant?
It was the only way.
Okay? The renovations, paying off my crew.
- It was the only way.
- Why would you do som...?
- I would never ask you to do that.
- I know you'd never.
Which is exactly why I had to do it.
It was my call, okay? It wasn't yours.
Besides, it's the first time
in a long time that I saw you happy.
So, for me, it was worth it.
Bruno… I know that that car
meant everything to you.
Yeah, well…
I guess you mean more.
I'm gonna make this up to you.
I promise you I'll make this all right.
This is gonna be
a great win for all of us.
You know, the next time a sheep's head
catches on fire, you call me.
Because judging by that crew,
there's gonna be another time.
- Capisce?
- Capisce.
I didn't mean it about your ma
and not being proud of you.
You can't take that back.
Those were terrible words.
That was terrible.
What?
Love you, buddy.
Meatballs, love them so
Thanks so much. Appreciate you.
Hey, Joe. Would you come outside?
We gotta show you something.
Yeah, let's go.
That's good for me
Let's have a glass of vino
Make it a tasty Pinot
Let's eat and drink and feel all right
And sing and dance…
Don't cry in front of the teamsters.
Go dish us up some panna cotta
Finish it off with a shot of…
All right, ladies.
If you can't see the camera,
camera can't see you.
Wait a second. Roberta, get in. Get in.
- Smile.
- Smiling!
- Good.
- Here we go.
- Hey.
- Everybody big smiles.
Come on!
- Manicotti!
- Come on!
I'm so grateful to all of you
who've been on this journey.
This is an exciting moment for all of us.
Tomorrow is the big day.
We got our menus, which is exciting.
We have these beautiful tables
and got a full house of wine.
But do we have any reservations? No.
Well, not exactly,
but everyone's been putting effort
into getting the word out,
so my expectation is tomorrow's
grand opening will be exactly that.
It is going to be grand.
- Right?
- Yes!
Knowing how busy we're gonna be
and you're gonna be, do me a favor.
Take the rest of today
to do whatever it is you need to do.
I have an idea.
Has everyone had their meds today?
- Yeah.
- Se.
Okay. Follow me.
I've got a surprise for you.
Okay. Thank you. It's gonna be great.
- I don't like surprises.
- Super exciting. Here, I'll help you.
Uh…
- I'll take the menu.
- I want it.
Okay, let's go.
- You got it.
- Olivia likes you.
Well, she's only human.
- She what?
- Only human.
I like her too.
Well, now do something about it, though.
Why are you being astunad?
- I don't know if she's ready for that.
- That's not for you to decide, is it?
- You know what my nonna used to say?
- No.
"Don't let old hurts get in the way
of a happy new beginning."
Well, I appreciate you.
Okay.
Anyway, make the move.
That's sweet.
Mind if I ask you for a favor?
All right.
Hi, Antonella.
Yeah, of course I'll pick you up.
Uh…
At the restaurant.
In an hour, after class.
Yeah. Okay, I'll see you there.
Come in. Come in, come in.
Whose place is this?
It's mine. I'm a hairdresser.
- Wow.
- Yes, have a seat.
So this is the salon.
Yeah, sit down.
When I was 16,
I started here sweeping the floors,
and then I worked in this chair,
and then all of the chairs,
and I worked, and I worked,
and I worked, and now,
I own the place.
That's why you always look so good.
Thank you. I think that women,
we deserve to feel beautiful, don't we?
Beauty, beauty, beauty. What's beauty?
That's a good question.
I mean, is it our hair?
Is it our faces or our bodies?
- Yes.
- No, no, no. It's a feeling.
Beautiful is a... is a feeling, like,
you feel beautiful, you know,
when you're seen, when you feel heard.
When you feel strong.
That's when you feel beautiful.
Beautiful.
So, now…
Let's celebrate beauty.
To have you all my own
I would have you mine alone
Oh.
I can't…
That's nice.
Tickles.
Oh, gee.
Oh, my God.
Wha… W…
How fabulous!
Forget it, get outta here!
Get away! Get away!
Gorgeous.
Antonella?
It's Olivia. Are you guys here?
Joe?
Wha…?
Are you guys…
Are you guys doing theme nights now?
Is this prom?
Oh…
The tux.
You forgot this.
The corsage?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
You look great.
- You do.
- Thank you.
Look at that.
We're right next to the punch bowl.
Keep a lookout for Mrs. Reynolds.
I thought maybe
I'd spice things up just a little bit.
Well, it's a little less rebellious
now that it's legal, but I will take one.
Cheers to the most beautiful
and funniest girl at the prom.
And the only girl at this prom.
- Cheers.
Hmm!
- Hmm.
- Ah!
Wow. Yeah, that's a good one.
Yeah.
Joe, this is the song.
May I?
I've never seen you looking
So lovely as you did tonight
I've never seen you shine so bright…
You may.
I've never seen so many men
Ask you if you wanted to dance
They're loking for a little romance…
It's nice to be having
this dance with you.
Given half a chance…
- But you have to make me a promise.
- Hmm.
I have never seen
That dress you're wearing…
Don't go putting a cape on me
because I'm such a great slow dancer.
I'm the same Joe you've always known.
Yep.
The lady in red…
Feels like a real prom.
- No, don't toast me. Just do it.
- Limoncello!
More Limoncello.
- You'll have such a headache tomorrow.
- Yeah, you gotta keep drinking some water.
- Water!
- One of these, six of these.
- Drink this water.
- Try some more. That's it. One more.
- Oh!
- Oh my.
- Yeah, okay. There you go. Okay.
Look at... Oh.
- What?
- Are your... Are your breasts real?
- Oh, my God.
- Yes.
- Oh. Really?
- No.
No, they're not. Here, feel. Here.
Oh! It's like... They're like gummy bears!
Fake breasts. I don't like them.
No.
Oh, I don't know.
After a double mastectomy, I kind of...
They grew on me.
- Oh.
- Oh, my God.
Mi dispiace.
- No, don't be sorry.
- I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry, I'm not.
You know.
They're gonna be perky forever.
- Forever.
- How about you?
- Well, they're…
- No, no.
- What?
- Not your breasts. What's your story?
Oh.
I'm sorry.
- You know, I had four kids, and…
- Uh-huh.
Well, they, yeah…
They don't talk to me.
I don't talk to them.
Why?
I'm a strong mother.
I brought them up to be strong
like my mama taught me.
Hmm.
I would've…
I would've done it different.
I… I would've loved them
differently now.
I understand.
It's okay.
Do you have children?
- No, no, I never married.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, no, don't be.
No, I mean, I love men. I do.
I love all kinds of men.
But, you know, for me, the idea
of one man for the rest of your life,
for your entire life,
that just seems like, I don't know,
just so impossibly boring, you know?
I never had a problem finding a man.
It was the women I had a problem with.
Women? Women? Why?
Well, I don't know, maybe I guess
the way I look and the way I am,
women were afraid
that I would steal their man.
That's crazy because
I would never steal another woman's man.
Well, you know, if my Gianni was alive,
which he's not, God bless his soul,
you wouldn't be my friend.
See?
Have you ever seen her wash dishes?
She's so sexy.
Oh. Angelo,
I would have paid you to take him.
Whatever you wanted,
I would have paid you.
You didn't deserve to be treated
like that. That wasn't right.
'Cause she's like a warm piece
of sweet Italian bread.
Aww.
Grazie.
Well, what about you?
Uh, who was the great love of your life?
Was there one?
Yes. There was one once.
Hmm?
What was his name?
Isabella.
Yeah, Isabella.
What happened?
Nothing. Nothing happened.
It was a sin. I left the convent.
And that's when... Oh.
It's not easy to live in a world
that rejects what you are.
Yes.
Oh, my God.
That's terrible.
No, no. Here. To Isabella.
- To Isabella.
- Isabella.
- To you, honey.
- To you.
- You deserve it.
Thank you all.
To you.
And Teresa.
- Bless you, darling.
- Oh.
Hmm.
And what about your family, Antonella?
Well, my Gianni
has been gone for many years.
But we had three beautiful children.
They live all over the country now.
Nine grandchildren.
Beautiful.
I don't see them very often,
but I'm very proud of them because
they're living their lives very well.
And that makes me very happy.
And, uh, thank you for today,
because this has been great, hasn't it?
- Here's to living our lives very well.
- Indeed.
- Yes, yes.
- Indeed!
Yes.
- So good.
- I've never stayed up all night.
- Gorgeous!
- Wow!
Grazie!
Look at these. You guys look beautiful.
- You can thank Gia for this.
- It's not the painter. It's the canvas.
I got drunk, but I don't have a hangover
because I had water.
Smart!
Hey, Joe, tonight we feed the world.
- Sì?
- Se!
Whoo!
It's showtime!
Opening night and we get a thunderstorm.
Hey, sorry we're late.
It's crazy weather out there.
- God.
- There she is. Our legal counsel.
Look at you.
- It's like we're back in high school.
- Oh, you wish you were in high school.
- Hello. Oh!
- Hello.
Oh, my God, Joe.
It really looks beautiful. Hmm.
Yeah.
You. You did good, you. Come here.
Yeah, it was nothing. Now, hey.
- For good luck, brother.
- Hey.
Thanks so much for coming, guys.
It's great seeing you.
Nice.
So is the, uh, dinner rush over?
Over?
- It didn't start yet.
- Yeah, it's been kinda slow.
How slow?
You are actually
our first customers tonight, so…
Joey, my brother, and his family,
they were gonna come here,
but I think they're afraid
of getting stuck in the storm.
They're from Philadelphia, so…
You know what? Here's the good news.
We got two lovely customers.
Let's give 'em an experience
they'll never forget, right?
- Right!
- Yes!
- Spoil 'em!
- I'll show you to your table.
All right.
So… Does this mean we have to pay?
Absolutely. Thank you so much for coming.
Okay…
Hmm.
Ladies, you have completely
outdone yourselves.
This is the greatest meal I've had since…
last night.
Truly. This really is
the best Italian cooking I have ever had.
Yeah, it's, uh…
It's getting kinda late.
I think we should call it here,
but, uh, terrific job. It's great.
If you're around…
Thank you, Aunt Teresa.
Thank you for coming.
There we go. Here's the news.
- For you.
- Joe!
- These are your paychecks.
- The restaurant hasn't earned a dime.
- Wait until things kick in, that's crazy.
- Absolutely not.
Every two weeks, you get a check.
It's been two weeks.
You're not working here for free.
That's your money, okay?
We'll figure it out.
- Joe.
- Why isn't anyone coming?
- Shame on you!
- Hey, what'd you do that for?
You're telling people not to come?
Is that what you're doing?
It ain't just me.
The entire neighborhood
wants that place gone.
I don't like that he's not from here,
and I don't like how
he's using you ladies as a gimmick.
Using me as a gimmick?
He's not using me!
He's celebrating me, youstunad.
- Come on.
- How dare you? How dare you?
- Antonella, hey!
- Shut up.
- Antonella, hey! Vieni cà.
- Leave me alone.
Joe's a good man.
He's not trying to take anything away.
He's trying to give something back.
Night, Joe.
- Good night.
- Night, Joe.
- Night.
- Good night, Joe.
- Night, Joe.
- See you later.
- Have a good night.
- Good night, Joey.
- How was class?
- It was good.
That's good.
So, how bad?
I think it's all over but the crying.
I've done everything I can think of.
I can't get anyone to come down here.
I've called the critics,
emailed the critics. I've done it twice.
I'm gonna end up on a restraining order
from some of these guys.
So, I was gonna wait and maybe,
you know, tomorrow,
just let everyone know there's no way
to keep this place open anymore.
Oh. No, no, no, you can't say that.
Wait a minute. If they won't come here,
maybe you should… you should go there.
Take it to them.
Maybe.
Oh, come on.
Sweetie,
the only thing at the end of the day
that you're gonna regret
are not the mistakes you make.
You can make your peace and move on.
You're gonna regret
the moments that you did not take,
and this is your moment, Joe.
- Mr. Durant?
- Oh?
Hi.
Uh, no.
Oh, let me start off by saying it's wildly
inappropriate to come barging in on you.
- My apologies.
- Who are you?
- I'm sorry. I'm Joe Scaravella.
- You can't just walk in. What's going on?
- I'm not walking in.
- I'm gonna call security.
- I'm opening an Italian restaurant.
- Hey, Michael.
Instead of hiring professional chefs…
- Taylor?
- …I hired nonnas to do the cooking.
Sure.
When people come in, I wanted them
to feel like when they were younger
and have the person who loved them
the very most in their life cook for them.
- Grandmothers are cooking for you?
- Yes, Italian grandmothers.
Uh-huh.
Are you some kind of insane person?
I'm a little bit crazy,
but not in a scary way.
Just passionate about food,
and I wanted to share this with you.
- No, don't...
- Can I just show you these dishes?
Look at this. This isstrangolapreti.
This right here, this has heirloom.
- Oh, my God.
- It has spinach, right?
- Ricotta.
- Oh boy.
Burro fusoand sage. It's just simple.
All from all different places in Italy
made by all different nonnas,
and they have cannolis here for dessert.
And it's all homemade.
All from nonnas. All from the grandmas.
All right.
Enoteca Maria.
Yes, Enoteca Maria, after my mom.
Staten Island.
Yes.
Um…
Yeah, Joe,
you realize I review restaurants
here in Manhattan.
You know, three-star, two-star, one-star
Michelin restaurants here and abroad.
Exactly. And that's why I'm here.
If you could, I'd love if you could review
Enoteca Maria this weekend.
Well, this weekend…
I am booked up until January.
So, next time you decide
to open a restaurant, maybe…
Plan better.
I can admit that.
There isn't a great business plan
in place for this place.
You're right about that.
But I do have a really good plan
for the restaurant.
Okay, 'cause it's not a restaurant.
It's really more about family,
and experiencing family.
Especially for people
who may not have family anymore.
The nonnas that are doing the cooking,
they're tremendous chefs.
I'm not coming in here
asking you to do us a favor.
I just want you to come down
and experience the restaurant
and just give it a fair shot.
I think it's pretty special.
- Pick up, pick up, pick up.
- Don't worry.
Pick up, pick up, pick up.
Ah, straight to voicemail, again.
I hope Joe's okay. That he's not hurt.
That he didn't fall or hurt his leg.
Maybe he's in the street.
Joe isn't hurt. He's just not showing up.
Oh, I know what you're saying.
And I don't like it.
Joe will be here!
Really?
What did I say?
No one cares about us,
about our cooking, about our stories.
Nobody cares.
We are discarded old artifacts.
Do you understand?
- That's what we are.
- Uh-uh-uh. You speak for yourself, woman.
- I don't believe that's true.
- We've been open for more than a month.
Who has come in other than
friends and family? We're unimportant.
Insignificant.
And no one is gonna
remember us for anything.
Okay. See the door?
Don't let it hit you
in the ass on the way out!
Because I'm something here!
This means something to me!
I'm not discarded,
and I don't feel discarded like you feel!
- Don't start with me. Enough already.
- Get out! We don't need you!
Silenzio! Please! I'm so ashamed of you.
We are not quitters. We do not walk away.
We're intelligent, strong women.
We're beautiful women
with Italian blood in our souls.
And we've been through too much together,
and I'm not gonna let this end in anger.
Well said.
Grazie.
All right.
- Okay.
- Okay, Bologna, come on.
Hey.
- Joe!
- How are you?
Hey, Joe.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Okay, whatever it is, it's gonna be okay.
I appreciate that.
Uh…
Well, honestly, I wish I had better news
because you guys were all terrific.
Honestly.
And you all definitely deserve
to keep this thing going.
Um…
You know, I think it's safe to say no one
wanted this thing to fly more than I did.
You know, not just for myself,
but for my mom.
But also, really, because of all of you.
And just how special
and how much you all mean to me.
But, uh…
The truth is, we're just not gonna
be able to keep these doors open.
And I say thank you and I'm sorry.
You…
You gave it your best shot.
And we're very proud of you.
You did good.
We all did our best, Joe.
Your mother would be proud.
Thank you.
She would.
Yeah.
You know what?
Now we're all like a family. Right?
So, if that's the one thing
that we get outta this,
then I think we've won. So, thank you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
"The family you choose."
That's us.
Oh, we got a problem.
We have a lot of food in that kitchen.
It would be a sin to throw it away, Joe.
Well, let's not.
Why don't we invite our family,
our friends, anyone we know,
and let's have one hell
of a Sunday night dinner?
- Yes!
- Great idea.
- Yes, a party.
- Am I right?
- Yes!
- With Limoncello!
- No!
- Wingman showed up. Nice to see you.
- Nice to see you. Good to see you.
- This is Olivia. These are my MTA guys.
- Vito. Nice to meet you.
- You guys sit wherever you want, okay?
- We're doing it family style.
- Say hi to cousin Tammy. Cousin Tammy!
- Hi! It's so nice to meet you!
- You look great. Nice to see you.
- Thank you. This is beautiful.
- Beautiful. My man, good to see you.
- Congrats.
Hey.
I just wanna let you know,
as soon as I sell the place,
I'm gonna pay you back every penny.
Hey, stop it. No. Tonight's about you.
None of that stuff matters.
Yeah. Come on, we're proud of you.
- Wanna show them where they're sitting?
- I'm starving. Come on.
Hey, you made it.
Thanks so much for coming.
- You look terrific.
- Joey.
Good to see you. Glad you're here tonight.
- Hey.
Uh…
I heard this is your last night.
I'm sorry about that.
I'm a businessman too,
and I wouldn't wish that on anybody, so…
It's a, you know, kind of an homage.
Part of the history of the building,
so we kept it.
It's beautiful. Thank you.
Well…
I… This is for you.
I'm just gonna take off.
No, no, no, sit down.
Have some food, crack this open,
I'll come and share a glass with ya, okay?
Come sit down and eat. Come in.
There's a lot of people out there
waiting to experience your hearts. Ready?
- Yes!
- Let's go!
- Ready!
- Okay.
That's a lot of salt!
- Coming up.
- Pour it.
Those look so good. Delicious!
Here, try this.
Hmm!
Okay, baby.
So good. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Pass this down.
Hey!
- Our nonnas would be proud.
- To our nonnas.
To the nonnas.
Excuse me.
Could you guys
all come out here for a second, please?
What'd we do?
All right.
Yeah!
Great job.
Hmm.
What's happening?
Well…
Well, I'm sorry to interrupt,
and I appreciate your time.
Thank you.
When my editor, Edward Durant,
asked me to review Enoteca Maria,
a new Italian restaurant located at
27 Hyatt Street, Staten Island, New York,
I was compelled to see
what hiring real-life nonnas
instead of established chefs
was all about.
But what I would soon discover
is that this quaint, little,
beautifully designed restaurant,
with a warm and inviting decor,
served up far more
than just delicious food.
It served family.
That's great!
- You did it, brother.
- We did it.
Beautifully designed, huh? Come on.
It served culture and history.
Attaboy, Joey!
It served generations worth
of traditions and stories.
So if you want just great food,
don't go to Enoteca Maria.
But if you want great food
that not only fills your stomach,
but will lift your soul,
then run, don't walk,
to a little slice of family
where you can let the one person
who loved you most in life
cook for you again.
And definitely order thecapuzzelle.
Hello?
Sadie?
Yes, this is Sadie.
It's Mama.
Ma?
Yeah.
Hi. Is everything okay?
Everybody was skeptical, but not me.
I said I would design this place,
and now look at what's going on here.
- "This is beautifully designed."
- Can I borrow you for a second, please?
All right, let's reload here.
Everything good?
- Amazing.
- Counselor?
- Look. You did this all.
- You kidding me? We did this.
Please. We need to hire another server,
because I got finals.
Again with the flowers?
Take a day off. Let her miss you.
- How's it going? Everything good?
- Couldn't be better, tesoro.
- What's the news, Magical?
- I'm in a wool sweater!
I'm sorry with the sheep's head
and the eyes, but it is selling.
- You have to admit, she's doing terrific.
- I'm working here.
I understand. I'll be right back.
I'm just gonna get some air.
- Have a good time, Joe.
- Yeah.
Proud of you guys.
I'll meet you any time you want
In our Italian restaurant
She took the ocean home to you
She saw the lady tall and true
She stood in line at Ellis Island
Wrote her name and took the highland
To the red, white and the blue
She found her dream of liberty
And what'd she give us? Italy!
She's our Nonna
She lived on Hyatt Street
She worked hard and found her joy
Then met a nice Italian boy
Her resolve, it never faltered
As they knelt there at the altar
And raised their little girl and boy
She found her dream of liberty
And what'd she give us? Italy!
She's our Nonna
She lived on Hyatt Street
So many dreams
So many names
We're all unique
And all the same
So for the millions of the faces
Who built the town
And left their traces
You're not alone
You've got a home on Hyatt Street
Buongiorno!
Arrivederci!
We took the ferry home to you
We saw the lady tall and true
We brought the kids to Ellis Island
Found your name and took the highland
To the red, white, and the blue
We are your dream of liberty
And what'd you give us? Italy!
You're our Nonna
You live on Hyatt
We can't deny it
It's never quiet Come home
To Hyatt Street